<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Ankur Patil</title>
    <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Ankur Patil</description>
    <image>
      <title>Ankur Patil</title>
      <url>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ankur12-1610.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My LFX Mentorship Journey with CNCF: Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/journey-lfx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/journey-lfx/</guid>
      <description>I have always wanted to participate in the LFX Mentorship program and here I am, graduated, writing this blog. These 3 months were amazing! This blog covers my experience in this mentorship.
What’s the LFX Mentorship? “The Linux Foundation Mentorship Program is designed to help developers — many of whom are first-time open source contributors — with necessary skills and resources to learn, experiment, and contribute effectively to open source communities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey: Getting Selected in Summer of Bitcoin &#39;22</title>
      <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/journey-sob/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/journey-sob/</guid>
      <description>On May 1, I received an email saying that I was one of the 82 interns selected amongst 20317 applicants for the Summer of Bitcoin 2022 program.
I was really happy and surprised as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any high hopes at that time. This blog covers my journey of getting selected into the program from the very beginning.
So everyone might be asking a question: What is Summer of Bitcoin?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access tokens for Specter&#39;s REST API: Part 2 | Summer of Bitcoin &#39;22</title>
      <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/sob-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/sob-part2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This blog covers the work that I&amp;rsquo;ve done post mid-term evaluation. In the last part, I implemented the token generation part which included generating and saving the token in the users.json file, which acts as the local database of the user.
Implementation Some things took a considerable amount of time and energy, as they needed to be discussed with the mentors.
Change in plans Initially, the data was stored in individual entities, which resulted in creating several hashmaps which weren&amp;rsquo;t necessary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access tokens for Specter&#39;s REST API: Part 1 | Summer of Bitcoin &#39;22</title>
      <link>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/sob-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ankur12-1610.github.io/posts/sob-part1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Specter Desktop is a desktop GUI for Bitcoin Core optimized to work with hardware wallets.
Specter already has a REST API system, but the authorization is currently done by HTTPBasicAuth and to improve the security, HTTPTokenAuth is really necessary. Access tokens would be a significant improvement.
My Project I have to use access tokens for the token-based authorization, the access token I opted for was JSON Web Token (JWT) because:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
